Some of y'all think that therapy is you sitting around and thinking about yourself, or you
going to the beach and thinking about yourself.
And I just want to say that is part of it.
But ultimately, if you don't have the tools yourself, how helpful is it for you to go
and sit and think about yourself by yourself?
You need supplementary materials.
You need outside perspective.
It's imperative.
It's like the niggas would be like, I read all these books.
Well, if you read all the books, but you just read them by yourself and you didn't actually
have to sit around and talk about them and hear other people's analysis and critical
thinking ideas, then how valuable was the learning truly?
Was there really retention or was it simply seen through the lens of your own egoism, of
your own perspective, of your own reality?
That is not intellectual.
That is not elevation.
And the same goes with how we examine ourselves.
And it doesn't mean that you have to be in, you know, sit down therapy all the time.
It doesn't mean that you have to be reading books all the time.
It doesn't mean that you have to be going to Reiki all the time.
But it does mean that you have to be dedicating some level of effort beyond just you and what
you have here in order to understand how you show up here.